fire away.
>> Mike, talk about Josiah Troder. What uh
what did you like about him? Only two
year worth of experience. You see a lot
of these college players staying in for
five and six years sometimes. What what
made him come out of the draft and and
what did you like about him? Yeah, I I
mean I'll say like this we drafted three
21 year olds, so that's it's been a a
rare instance recently with the co
stuff, but uh I think Jeremiah, he's
just been groomed to to play football
his whole life, you know, growing up
with his dad and his brother, you know,
getting drafted a few years ago. And um
he had made a well-informed decision is
what I would say. Like he he thought he
was ready to come out and we spent a lot
of time with him through this process
and um his play on the field dictated
that too, I think. How much are you
influenced by a relationship like with
Mike Caldwell and stuff like that?
>> Yeah, I mean I think all that stuff
helps, right? Just to try to get to know
the player. Um, yeah, Mike had a
relationship with Todd has a
relationship with his dad, too. Um, you
know, and again, we spent a lot of time
with him, too, and just came away
feeling really comfortable. But I think
all that matters, you know, just again
trying to find out everything we can
about these kids and and uh that played
a part in it.
>> The perception is that you guys needed
to improve some of your pass defense
inside with with the linebacker
position. I know you got picked up some
free agents obviously, but
>> for for Troder seem to be more of a of a
run player right now at least, right?
>> Yeah. I mean, I I would say that's
that's fair, but I also think that he he
can play in coverage. I think he's
that's a little bit of a misnomer and
you know, I don't know if it's the
narrative that the media is putting out,
but like he's actually pretty good at
it. Now, that being said, he's an old
school downhill Mike backer that can
play the run, which is hard to find
nowadays. I mean, with the college game,
the way it's went, it's all lateral and
everybody's looking for the speed stuff.
And to us, he has enough speed to play
in our our league. Um, now, if you said,
is he a better run defender than than
pass defender? I would say, yeah, that's
probably fair, but we think he has a
capability to be a three down
linebacker.
>> Talk about his blendability in that
matter.
>> Yep. And I would say that's that's a big
part of his game, too. I mean, he he
understands how to rush the passer and
and he can go through running back's
faces if he chooses to or he can make
them miss. So, that's going to be a plus
for Todd on third downs. I mean, you
guys have seen the way that he uses our
inside backers when Devin was here. And
I mean, I would I would anticipate
Josiah having a lot of production in
that phase.
>> With with the fact that I mean, he's
only had like two years of college ball
experience. Would you expect him to kind
of grow in in his coverage and his
recognition and his instincts in that
department?
>> Yeah, 100%. I mean, all these guys are
like like I said, when I started, we
drafted three 21 year olds and we think
the upside with all of them are is is
huge. So, um, yeah, but I would say that
he also has played the game for a long
time and again has been kind of groomed
from from a young age. So, he's he's
pretty far advanced, I would say, in
that in that area.
>> I don't know if you could also speak to
the the because I I understand he's had
a few knee injuries between college. I
know in 2023 he had a torn I think it
was an ACL and then I think he had like
it was an MCL as well or like I mean did
you guys feel comfortable? I'm guessing
you felt comfortable with the medical. I
mean, I I would say anytime we get asked
a question like that, the answer is
always going to be yes. We're
comfortable with it. Otherwise, we
wouldn't even mess around with it. I
mean, our doctors and athletic trainers,
they do a heck of a job and they spend
tons of time on all these guys. So, if
we select somebody, we're we're
certainly comfortable with.
>> What do you see out of this maybe
leadership potential maybe further down
the road? You know, where's the green
dot? And, you know, you see him talking
to us, especially with the linebacker
room that obviously lost a big time
leader. You know, maybe down the line,
what do you see out of him in that
sense? Yeah, I mean it's I'm never going
to compare anybody to Levonte David,
first of all, but uh he uh he has those
qualities though as far as the potential
to be have an impact on our defense and
the in the locker room as a whole. Um
he's just he's he just gets the game
too. So he's if all the the resources we
talked to or the the sources we talked
to at the school spoke very highly of
him and not only his ability to learn
but also his ability to help others
learn and he would come in every week
and have it like a cheat sheet and tips
for the other players in the room and
helping them out. So he's well on his
way to being a leader now. He's got to
get here and and get in the locker room
and prove it to the to these veterans.
But uh he's got a chance to be pretty
good. I think
>> Mike in losing Evans you guys need a
true X receiver. So, does Hurst
obviously fill that role? And what is it
you you really like about Yeah, your
room is
>> plentiful as it is.
>> So, first of all, with Mike, like we
never ever going to try to replace Mike,
but but you do try to replace size and
speed, which Mike had, and and we think
that Ted has that, too. So Ted's a he's
a small school guy that, you know,
started out Vald Dasa, transferred to
Georgia State. Um, played a couple years
there. Had opportunities to go, you
know, to bigger schools with the NIL
stuff and and stayed loyal to Georgia
State, which it's kind of refreshing a
little bit in this day and age that uh
that guys choose to do that sometimes.
Now, you can look at it the other way
that he's not choosing to go up and play
against the best competition and stuff
like that, but a guy like Ted goes to
the Senior Bowl and does that and then,
you know, proves that he can do that as
well. So, he's just kind of checked the
boxes every step of the way. Um, and at
the same time, he's still has a lot to
improve on, you know, the route running
that. I mean, he's he's got he's just
kind of a raw player, but he's a he's a
big fast athletic guy that's willing to
learn and and we're excited about him.
>> The I mean, for him, is it is it the
contested catches? is that I mean I know
again there's no replacing Mike but you
know he's also that guy that if you need
to score quickly and you can get him you
know single coverage downfield you know
you're taking that shot. Um I know that
he has produced a lot of of catches of
20 plus yards. I mean is that kind of I
guess what you could envision for him?
>> Yeah I think so. I mean again like we're
talking about bringing a guy into a
crowded room to use your your quote
earlier. I mean, we're not expecting him
to come in and just, you know, take over
and and have to to be a big part of our
offense. Now, that being said, there's
nothing that says he can't if he comes
in and proves himself. He, you know,
whatever role he has, it's going to be
on what he's ready for and how he works
and proves himself. But, but yes, he is
a big guy that's 6'4, 210 and and runs
in the 44. So, that's intriguing to us,
you know. Um, and again, the downfield
stuff, he's got really good ball skills,
too. So, not only can he get over the
top and beat guys deep, but if it is
contested, he has the ability to make
those catches. So, u he's got a lot of a
lot of traits that we look for at at the
X position, which is what Mike played.
And, um, and we'll just see how it all
all plays out.
>> So, a factor like is is a big slot. I
know that that Zach likes to use that.
That's how we use Drake London and
Atlanta quite a bit with slant catches,
getting yards after catch with that
speed.
>> Yeah. I mean, again, like I have
complete faith in in our coaches, uh,
that they're going to put him in great
positions and and I wouldn't rule that
out. I mean, I just think that, you
know, there's there's three sometimes
four, sometimes five white outs on the
field and they're going to put them in
spots where they're going to be able to
succeed and and he has a skill set to do
that. You know, it's just when you see
the size and the speed, everybody thinks
outside, but we've been pretty
successful putting bigger guys inside as
well, you know, and Chris can do that,
Mecca can do that. like we got some guys
that can do it, but if to to get
matchups, that's what this game's all
about is matchups and and he has the
ability to do a lot of different things.
>> You guys let Jason trade this year. Um
how how important was for you guys to
get one of those extra day day three
picks in?
>> Yeah, we were actually joking about
that. It was time for us to trade back
and get an extra pick with Jason. Uh
that's that's always interesting
especially in a draft like this where I
think it probably wasn't like topheavy
but I think there's a lot of depth and a
lot of quality players in those you know
mid rounds to even the fifth round which
you know we picked up that pick. So it's
always good to get more picks. I mean we
feel like we can we can hit on those
later rounds. Our scouting department
does a heck of a job of you know of of
identifying those guys that so that we
look at them too and and uh we've had a
pretty good hit rate around here recent.
you guys sweating it out as as as 84
came back up.
>> Uh I mean, you're always going to sweat
it out. Like that's just kind of part of
the draft because you're dealing with 31
other teams that are, you know, doing
the same thing you are. So, um but at
the same time, we trade back. We know
that there's a chance we're going to
lose him, but so we're always prepared
to have other guys lined up if that's
the case. But but yes, when uh when our
pick came up and he was still there, it
was pretty pretty exciting in the room.
>> What did you see first in the in the
senior bowl? you mentioned, you know,
stepping up and playing up against, you
know, tougher competition. What What did
you see from him there?
>> Just his ability to compete and and and
hold up versus those guys. Um, it wasn't
too big for him, which is always kind of
what you look for from smaller school
players if they can go there and
compete. And it was like, I mean, I
always use Alli Maretta as a perfect
example, like Alli went there coming
from Hobart College and struggled the
first day, but by the end of the week,
he was he was kicking everybody's ass.
So, that was always it's it's those
small school guys, that's what they have
to do. First of all, they have to
dominate their their level of
competition. If they're not doing that,
then it's hard to project them in our
league. But if they are and then they
can go to the Senior Bowl and or the any
of these all-star games really and hold
their own, then it gives you, you know,
encouragement that they'll be able to do
it in our level.
>> Mike, last night we saw a pretty excited
uh Bucks war room and selecting Ruben
Bane Jr. Uh what are your thoughts uh
overall about being able to land him in
the process in which you you got him?
>> Yeah, that's that's probably one of the
more excited draft rooms I've been
around of. I mean, it just when you get
a player of his quality um where we were
picking, I think that's what where the
excitement comes from. Um because a lot
of us didn't expect him to be there. We
just assumed he was going to be long
gone. But again, that's why we prepare
for every scenario and we did a lot of
work on Ruben just like we do every
other prospect. and um it it's just fun
to to see him there uh because we think
we're getting one of the better pass
rushers in this draft. And he brings a
lot of attitude and and effort and just
some nastiness that we've kind of been
lacking a little bit I think on defense
and I would say that Jeremiah has that
stuff too just what I was talking about
the run stuffer downhill type player. So
uh it's exciting to add those two young
guys to our defense. Speaking of that,
you look at edge rusher and linebacker
and those were two of the biggest needs
coming into this this offseason with
Bane in the first round with Troder in
the second round. How does it feel how
for you guys? Are you comfortable
knowing that hey, we might have just
locked up two starters for the first and
fixed this position that was one of the
ones that we kind of set into this offse
to fix.
>> Yeah, I I mean I think that that's what
you always go into a draft hoping that
the needs match up with the best player
and I think that's kind of what happened
in this draft. I mean, I don't think
that Jason, we never force things and
again, I don't think we did this year
either. I just think that just happened
to be, you know, the best player was
there and it's two positions that, you
know, I would agree we probably needed
to to upgrade a little bit. And um yeah,
it's pretty exciting to think that, you
know, and we'll see. I mean, what it's
too early to call them starters, but
you're drafting in the first and second
round, you're expecting to come in and
compete for that role. So, we'll see how
it all plays out, but yeah, it's pretty
exciting.
>> What was what was it that sold you on on
Bane? I mean, because this is this is a
class where there's a lot of of edge
rushers and we've seen so many so many
come off the board.
>> He's different because just because of
the body type, you know, he's a shorter,
thicker guy, but his power is unmatched
in my opinion. Like he he has the
ability to go through blockers faces,
which is a that's a good place to start
as a pass rush in our league. I mean,
everybody talks about all the speed guys
that can can run the hoops, but it's
hard to get around Tristan Warfs. I
mean, he's just as athletic as a lot of
these guys and it's tough and it's tough
to get around him. So, you got to be
able to incorporate some kind of power
into your game and he has that already.
So, now it's just a matter of him
continuing to hone his skills and um and
be able to to use change ups which he's
already done a lot of. I mean, he had a
really good defensive line coach there
at Miami and he's probably pretty far
ahead of the game compared to a lot of
guys. Mike, there were a couple other uh
linebackers there for the taking in the
second round, but what was the the
factor in selecting Josiah over some of
the other guys?
>> I mean, in the end, it's about the
player and the person, right? And we
just thought he was one of those guys
that matched up with both of them. Like,
he has, you know, he has a lot of
ability to play in this league. And
again, I just talked about the toughness
and the and the attitude that a guy like
him brings to our defense. Um, and then
the person and the leader that we think
that he could potentially be and the
teammate. I mean, he he just fits kind
of the the I am that man that we use a
lot around here.
>> Mike, with with Troder, I think he had
27 reps on the bench at combine. He's
the most by a linebacker in like four
years at combine. I just ask about his
physicality and what that brings to the
position for you guys.
>> Yeah, I mean, again, I think that's you
you don't see that a lot in co the
college game now. Like I said before, I
mean, it's just the ability to go on and
take on these big offensive linemen and
use that ability to press and get off
blocks. I mean, he he's pretty rare in
that in that sense from from a college
guy coming out like um so he's just to
me like he's so much further ahead of
the game being able to adapt to a pro
style game as opposed to what you know a
lot of these guys coming out of college.
It's it's probably a bigger learning
curve than what he's going to have. How
do you kind of weigh what his strengths
are versus because as he mentioned like
there are other guys on the that were
still available like CJ Allen he was
still on the board I think at the time.
Um, I know that Jacob Rodriguez has
already had already been picked, but
like how do you weigh like what his
strengths are? You know, he's a thumper
and and very physical, uh, versus like,
okay, maybe getting more of like an
ancilloney type, you know, where he's
more of a of a coverage type of a
player. Like, how did you kind of, I
guess, come to the decision of of which
style you wanted, you know, because two
in free agency, you know, you signed
different guys,
>> right? I mean, there's so many things
that go into selecting a player, and I
would say that we had all those guys
pretty closely clumped together. I mean,
they're all really good football
players. So, um